Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Joseph O'Donnell Papers, 1947-1987 and undated, bulk 1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Joseph O'Donnell papers 1947-1987 and undated, bulk 1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
12 linear feet Extent: 6000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Joseph O'Donnell was an executive with JWT and served as the company's Chief Executive Officer during 1986. The Joseph O'Donnell Papers cover the years 1947-1987, with the bulk of materials from 1986, the year O'Donnell served as Chief Executive Officer of JWT. The collection primarily consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports of company performance, presentations and company policy information. The collection also includes personnel-related records, photographs, and videocassettes of television commercials of JWT and competing agencies. Companies represented in the collection include Beatrice Foods; Kodak; Ford; Hyatt Hotels; IBM; Kellogg's; Kraft; Pepsi-Cola; Sprint; Unilever; and U.S. Air. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00736
Language: Material in English, Spanish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
RESTRICTED: Files relating to personnel matters of JWT employees are closed to research for 40 years from the date of termination of employment, or 25 years from the date of the employee's death if termination date is unknown.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be made.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Joseph O'Donnell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Biographical Note
1942 May 11 Born Joseph William O'Donnell, Newton, Mass.
1964 B.A., Economics, Columbia University
1965-1971 U.S. Marine Corps; attained rank of Sergeant
1967 Columbia University Business School
1976 Account representative, JWT New York Office
1978 Office Manager, JWT Detroit Office
1982 Promoted to head of JWT Chicago Office
1986 March Chief Executive Officer of JWT
1987 January Fired from JWT following a failed buy-out attempt
1987-1989 Served as Chief Executive Officer of Campbell-Mithun-Esty
1988-1989 Served as Chairman of Campbell-Mithun-Esty
Joseph O'Donnell began his career in advertising as a Traffic Department trainee at Doyle Dane Bernbach, later as an assistant account executive on DDB's Heinz account. O'Donnell advanced to become Account Executive, Account Supervisor and then Vice President of that account. He served as a partner at Cox & Company for two and a half years, where he headed the accounts of Burlington Sheets and Saab. In 1976, he began working for JWT New York, where his first assignment was with the Samsonite account. During his ten years at JWT, O'Donnell served in an executive capacity on several major accounts, including Ford; Kodak; McDonnell Douglas; Chrysler; Kraft Foods; Sears; Kellogg's; and Sprint.
Following his tenure at Campbell-Mithun-Esty, O'Donnell served as Chairman and Chief Executive of Consumer Research in Manchester, Vermont; and he also founded a cable television network called the Consumer Resource Network.
Collection Overview
The Joseph O'Donnell Papers cover the years 1947-1987, with the bulk of materials from 1986, the year O'Donnell served as Chief Executive Officer of JWT. The collection primarily consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports of company performance, presentations and company policy information. The collection also includes personnel-related records, photographs, and videocassettes of television commercials of JWT and competing agencies. Companies represented in the collection include Beatrice Foods; Kodak; Ford; Hyatt Hotels; IBM; Kellogg's; Kraft; Pepsi-Cola; Sprint; Unilever; and U.S. Air.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into nine series: Administrative Files, Client Files, Correspondence, International Offices, Meetings, Personnel, Reports, Writings and Speeches, and Audiovisual Materials. The Administrative Files Series includes memoranda, correspondence, company policy information, leases, clippings, photographs and financial documents pertaining to the daily operations of JWT domestic offices. The Client Files Series includes campaign presentations, marketing plans, briefings, correspondence, agency reviews and annual reports pertaining to specific JWT clients, as well as general information on JWT client policies. The Correspondence Series contains correspondence and memoranda from JWT-sponsored charities, clients, newspapers and organizations, as well as memoranda between JWT employees. The International Offices Series contains primarily memoranda between JWT employees and clients in international offices, as well as some materials from international advertising conferences and meetings. The Meetings Series contains programs, correspondence, schedules, itineraries, and some presentation slides related to JWT meetings and events, as well as materials pertaining to general advertising events. The Personnel Series contains correspondence and resumes pertaining to company hires, terminations, salaries and bonuses, along with performance reviews and information on employee stock holdings. The Reports Series includes plans, company performance reviews, budgets and yearly reports relating to JWT and its subsidiaries. The Writings and Speeches Series contains scripts, notes and visual materials related to speeches and formal presentations given by JWT employees at company events, as well as at events of general advertising organizations. The Audiovisual Materials Series includes film compilations of advertising spots of JWT clients, as well as clients of competitive companies.
Restrictions on Access: Files relating to personnel matters of JWT employees are closed to research for 40 years from the date of termination of employment, or 25 years from the date of the employee's death if termination date is unknown. In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be made.
Subject Headings
O'Donnell, Joseph William, 1942-; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; Beatrice Foods Company; Eastman Kodak Company; Ford Motor Company; Hyatt Hotels Corporation; International Business Machines Corporation; Kellogg Company; Kraft Foods Company; Pepsi-Cola Company; Unilever (Firm); US Airways; Sprint Corp; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Photographs; Videocassettes; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Biographical Information
Chicago Office Records
Detroit Office Records
Iconographic Collection
Arnold Grisman Papers
Don Johnston Papers
Norman H. Strouse Papers
Contents of Collection
- Administrative Files, 1947-1987 and undated, (1 box)
  Contains memoranda, correspondence, company policy information, leases, clippings, photographs and financial documents pertaining to the daily operations of JWT domestic offices. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Agency profile, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Atlanta office space, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Business Building Efforts forms, undated (Box 1)
  - Chicago lease, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1947, 1983, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Joe O'Donnell clippings, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Corporate Committee, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Council of Better Business Bureaus, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Creative Director profiles, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Advertising Association, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Directors expenses, 1986 (Box 1)
  - JWT Group
    - General files, 1981, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Policies and procedures, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Press, 1981, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Number of Offices, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Patterson, Jim (Executive Vice President) photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1981-1982 and undated (Box 1)
  - Policy on Reporting of Billings, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Salvation Army, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Subscriptions and memberships, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Tampa Group Move, Relocation Policy and Program Guide, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Thompson Recruitment Advertising, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
- Client Files, 1981-1987 and undated, (6 boxes)
  Includes files pertaining to JWT client policies, strategies and reports, as well as materials specific to particular companies. Includes campaign presentations, marketing plans, briefings, correspondence, agency reviews and some client-specific annual reports. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - General files
    - Client briefing letters, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Client development plan, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Client media pressure, 1985 Feb. (Box 1)
    - Court/Money, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Key clients
      - Agency contact, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Dates, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Multinational Client Business Building Program, 1984 (Box 1)
    - New Business, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Presentation, slides not used, undated (Box 2)
    - Production costs, 1985 Feb. (Box 2)
    - Top 20 Worldwide Clients, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Warning letters, 1985 Feb. (Box 2)
      [Form letters expressing similar dissatisfaction with JWT, addressed from a variety of clients]
  - AT&T/Illinois Bell, 1982 Nov. 29 (Box 2)
  - Beatrice Foods
    - General files, 1980-1983, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Business Units profiles, 1983 (Box 2)
    - McRobbie meeting, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Meeting agenda, 1983 Oct. 18 (Box 2)
  - Burger King, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Chevron, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Continental Airlines, 1986 (Box 2)
  - DeBeers, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Discover Card, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Eastman Kodak
    - General files, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Account briefing, 1986 June (Box 2)
    - Worldwide Management Review, 1986 May 9 (Box 2)
  - Eaton, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Evans Furs, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Ford (Box 3)
    - General files, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Ford Division Car Creative Review, 1986 Mar. 26 (Box 3)
    - Detroit office, 1986 (Box 3)
    - D.E. Petersen meeting, 1986 Sept. 23 (Box 3)
  - General Foods, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Gerber, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
  - Goodyear, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - H&R Block, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Hill & Knowlton
    - General files, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Strategic Plan Review, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Hyatt Hotels
    - General files, 1981-1986, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Plans Board, 1981 July 24 (Box 3)
  - IBM
    - General files, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Mid-Range Competitive Positioning--A Creative Overview, undated (Box 3)
    - Presentation, 1986 July 9 (Box 3)
    - Review Board briefing, undated (Box 3)
  - Kellogg Company (Box 4)
    - General files, 1981-1986, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - International Case History, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Proposed Agenda: Contingency Planning Session, undated (Box 4)
    - U.S. Broadcast Review, 1983 Feb. 14 (Box 4)
  - Kraft Foods Co.
    - General files, 1983, 1986, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Better for You campaign, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Business summaries, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Management Review, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Miracle Whip Communications Workshop Pre-Test, Carry Out, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Monthly Monitoring of JWT Performance on Kraft U.S. Branded Business, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Monthly Monitor of JWT Performance on Kraft RFG Business, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Singles campaign, 1983 (Box 5)
    - UDIA, undated (Box 5)
  - Löwenbräu, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Mattel, 1986 (Box 5)
  - McDonnell Douglas, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Midwest Bell
    - General files, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Brief Profile of JWT Chicago, 1983 May 4 (Box 5)
    - Presentation, 1983 Mar. 23 (Box 5)
  - Nabisco, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Nestlé
    - General files, 1986 (Box 5)
      [Includes international offices.]
    - Annual Agency Review, 1986 Apr. 2 (Box 5)
  - Nutri-Grain, marketing plans, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Pepsi-Cola
    - General files, 1986 (Box 5)
    - O'Donnell-Bowen Brief, 1986 Sept. 16 (Box 5)
  - Philips, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Pillsbury, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Procter & Gamble
    - General files, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Annual Report, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Reader's Digest, 1986 (Box 5)
  - R.J. Reynolds
    - General files, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Ross Johnson files, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Rolex (London), 40th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Rountree/Nestlé, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Salada Tea, Preliminary T-Plan, 1981 June 23 (Box 6)
  - S.C. Johnson
    - General files, 1981-1984, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - JWT International Overview, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Seven-Up, test market screw-up, 1985 Feb. (Box 6)
    [Inquiry regarding miscommunication relating to the launch of 7-Up 3-liter bottles]
  - Texas Air, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Unilever
    - General files, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Johnson-Lever Situation, Back-Up Materials, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Unilever-McNeil Pharmaceuticals, New Business Pitch, 1986 Oct. 18 (Box 6)
  - United Way
    - General files, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
    - Joseph O'Donnell Briefing, circa 1987 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Air, 1986 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Marine Corps, 1986 (Box 6)
  - U.S. Sprint
    - General files, 1986 (Box 6)
    - San Francisco presentation, 1986 Apr. 1 (Box 6)
  - Warner-Lambert, 1986 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1981-1987, (4 boxes)
  Contains correspondence and memoranda from JWT-sponsored charities, clients, newspapers and organizations, as well as memoranda between JWT employees. Also includes some private correspondence received by O'Donnell on the occasion of his 1986 promotion. Some of the letters arrived in Chronological Books. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Advertising Age, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Advertising Age article, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Administrative costs, 1986 (Box 6)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies (4As), 1985-1986 (Box 6)
  - American Advertising Federation, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Anniversaries, 1986-1987 (Box 6)
  - Asia Pacific Managers Meeting, 1986 Mar. (Box 7)
  - Boys Club of America, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Brouillard, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
  - Business Practices Questionnaire, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Chronological Books, 1986-1987, (1-7 of 8 folders) (Box 7)
  - Chronological Books, 1986-1987 (continued), (8 of 8 folders) (Box 8)
  - Club memberships, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Company Board, 1986-1987 (Box 8)
  - Compensation, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Conference Board, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1986, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Contributions, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Election of Officers, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Financial, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
  - International Herald Tribune, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Memoranda, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
  - New Years letters, 1986 (Box 9)
  - New York Post, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Joseph O'Donnell files, boards and committees, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Tampering, 1986 (Box 9)
    [Refers to an Ad Council campaign concerning corporate tampering]
  - Washington, D.C., Kemper Open, 1981-1983 (Box 9)
  - 466 Lexington, 1986 (Box 9)
- International Offices, 1985-1987, (2 boxes)
  Contains primarily correspondence and memoranda between JWT employees and clients in international offices. Includes some materials from international advertising conferences and meetings, as well as reviews of company performance. Items arranged alphabetically by office location.
  - Amsterdam, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Athens, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Caracas, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Central Pacific, 1986 November Review (Box 9)
  - China
    - General files, 1986 (Box 9)
    - JWT in China: Planning Cycle, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Dinner requests, 1985 Feb. (Box 9)
  - Europe
    - General files, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
    - EMG meeting minutes, 1986 Sept. 18 (Box 9)
    - EROC meeting, 1986 June 3 (Box 9)
  - Frankfurt
    - Multi-national JWT Policeman, 1985 Feb. (Box 9)
    - Organizational Study for JWT Germany, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Trip file, 1986, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Helsinki, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Hong Kong
    - Beijing Ad Conference, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Presentation, 1986 Oct. 3-8 (Box 10)
  - International client structure, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Japan, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Latin America, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Latin American Managers Meeting, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Lisbon, 1986 (Box 10)
  - London
    - General files, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
    - London trip, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Three-year plans, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Madrid, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Milan, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Singapore, 1986 (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Status Report on Asia, South Pacific, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Stockholm, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Sydney, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Toronto, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Turkey, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Vancouver, 1986 (Box 10)
- Meetings, 1981-1986, (2 boxes)
  Contains programs, correspondence, schedules, itineraries, and some presentation slides related to JWT meetings and events. Also includes materials pertaining to general advertising events. Folders were titled by organizing group and arranged alphabetically.
  - Advertising Managers Group, 1986 Mar. (Box 10)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies Annual Meeting, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Board Dinner, 1986 May 7, Evviva (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1984-1986, (1-2 of 7 folders) (Box 10)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1984-1986, (5-7 of 7 folders) (Box 11)
  - Davos Symposium materials, packet and slides, 1986-1987, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Dinners, Thompson tables, 1986 (Box 11)
  - European Managers Meeting, 1986 Mar. (Box 11)
  - Latin American Managers Meeting, 1986 Mar. (Box 11)
  - Managers' Meeting, JWT-USA, 1984 Sept. 11 (Box 11)
  - Sam Meek Seminar, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Newly Elected Board of Directors meeting, 1985 May 9, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - New York Board Group presentation, 1981 (Box 11)
  - No Trust Slides, undated (Box 11)
  - Operation Group meeting, 1985 Sept. (Box 11)
  - Operation Management Group meetings, 1986 (Box 11)
  - PDG, 1986 (Box 11)
  - VFW meeting, 1986 (Box 11)
- Personnel Files, 1985-1987 [RESTRICTED], (1 box)
  Contains primarily correspondence and resumes pertaining to company hires, terminations, salaries and bonuses. Also includes some performance reviews and information on employee stock holdings. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically by last name, where applicable.
  [Restrictions on access: Files relating to personnel matters of JWT employees are closed to research for 40 years from the date of termination of employment, or 25 years from the date of the employee's death if termination date is unknown.]
  - Agnew, Jim, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Balestrino, Chuck, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Beauregard, Bob, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Bonuses, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Brussels, 1986 (Box 12)
    [Primarily consists of files relating to the Pierre Puvilland investigation.]
  - Chairman visitation, 1985 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Chicago, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Clark, Harry, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Cooper-Evans, Michael, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Credentials, 1985 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Dell, Glen, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Detroit, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Diane's master file in machine, 1985 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Europe, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Gill, Mike, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Gutierrez, Victor, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Hore, Marlene, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Interview request, 1985 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Job Interview Endorsement, 1985 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Johnston, Don, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Kenyon, Vic, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Lane, Bill, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Lanigan, Denis, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Los Angeles, 1986 (Box 12)
  - MacMaster, Norm, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Manchester, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Manning, Burt, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Martens, Tom, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Martin, Terry, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Memoranda, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Metter, Bert, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
  - O'Brien, Wally, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Peters, Jack, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Petersen, Burt, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Rogers, Ken, 1986 (Box 12)
  - San Francisco, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Stock Incentive Plan Awards, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Stock Options, 1986 (Box 12)
  - U.S.A. General, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Washington, 1986 (Box 12)
- Reports, 1981-1987, (2 boxes)
  Includes plans, company performance reviews, budgets and yearly reports relating to JWT and its subsidiaries. Items arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Brouillard Communications Regional Review, 1986 Nov. (Box 13)
  - Chicago Office, marketing plan, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Europe Region, November Reviews, 1986 (Box 13)
  - JWT America Latina, November Review, 1986 Nov. 25 (Box 13)
  - JWT Group Reviews, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Management Incentive Plan, 1986 (Box 13)
  - May Operating Reviews, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Monthly Managers' Assessment Report, 1986 (Box 13)
  - New York Office Operational Review, 1986 Nov. 24 (Box 13)
  - Operational Reviews, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Professional Services Group
    - 1987 Plan and Budget, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Review of 1986 Plans (Box 13)
  - Retirement Trust Status Reports, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Thompson Recruitment Advertising, Inc., 1987 Plans Submission, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Thompson Company Monitoring Report, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Three Year Historical Review, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Year 1986 in Review, 1987 (Box 14)
- Writings and Speeches, 1983-1986 and undated, (4 boxes)
  Contains scripts, notes and visual materials related to speeches and formal presentations given by JWT employees at company events, as well as at events of general advertising organizations. Items were arranged alphabetically by speech title, where available, or by venue title.
  - Advertising Managers Group meeting, 1986 May 7 (Box 14)
  - Advertising speech, undated (Box 14)
  - Agency Breakfast, 1985 June 3 (Box 14)
  - Agate Club Speech, 1983 May 9 (Box 14)
  - Agency Review
    - Chicago, 1985 (Box 14)
    - Financial, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Beatrice tape, undated (Box 14)
  - Become the Leading International Advertising Agency, 1985 Sept. 12 (Box 14)
  - Board meetings, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - CEO presentation, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Charts for account presentation, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Company Profile Presentation, 1986 May, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Competitive Analysis Presentation to the Board of Directors, 1986 Sept. 11 (Box 15)
  - Copy Development Process Presentation, 1985 May 3 (Box 15)
  - Corporate Orientation, 1984 Oct. 25-26 (Box 15)
  - Creative Marketplace...in Target Groups, 1984 May (Box 15)
  - Employee Review-Compensation presentation, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Expectations of Our People, Epcot Center, World Meeting, 1984 May (Box 15)
  - FDAF Chairmen presentation, 1986 May 29 (Box 15)
  - Financial Division, State of the Agency, 1983 Apr. 1 (Box 15)
  - Group Board Meeting presentation, 1986 Dec. 2 (Box 15)
  - Helsinki speech, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Helsinki talk on JWT logo, 1986 Nov. (Box 16)
  - Hong Kong speech, 1986 Oct. (Box 16)
  - Institute of Outdoor Marketing, 1985 Mar. (Box 16)
  - Joe's quotes (slides), undated (Box 16)
  - JWT-Chicago: An Assessment of 1983 (Box 16)
  - George Lazarus Roast, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Management Development Recruitment, 1986 (Box 16)
  - Burt Manning Consumer Speech, 1984 Aug. (Box 16)
  - Media Nights, 1983 Nov. (Box 16)
  - Milwaukee Ad Club, 1986 Jan. 22 (Box 16)
  - Mission Statement, undated (Box 16)
  - Newly Directed Board of Directors meeting presentation, 1986 Mar. 8 (Box 16)
  - Operating Group Dinner presentation, 1983 Nov. 1 (Box 16)
  - Operations Group presentations and speeches
    - Financial Review, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Speeches, 1984 and undated (Box 16)